web-development-blog.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy | Web Development Blog

This site falls under the law and the rules of the Dutch Authority for Personal data and and is hosted from Europe (United Kingdom and / or the Netherlands). This site is owned and operated by finalwebsites.com (Schermhorst 107, 7009LM Doetinchem, The Netherlands) and all questions concerning privacy should be directed initially to Olaf Lederer (privacy@finalwebsites.com)

## Personal data that we process

finalwebsites.com processes your personal data if you are a client and make use of our services and / or if you chose to share your data with us.

Below is an overview of the personal data that we process:

  * First- and Last name
  * Email address
  * Location data (IP address)

### Special and / or sensitive personal data that we process

Our website and / or service does not have the intention to collect data of website visitors who are under the age of 16. Unless they have permission from a parent or guardian. However, we can not check if a visitor is older than 16. We also recommend parents to be involved in the online activities of their children, to avoid the data collection of children without parental consent. If you are convinced that we have collected personal information without the consent of a minor, please contact us via privacy@finalwebsites.com Subsequently, we will immediately delete the data of the minor.

## Why do we need data?

finalwebsites.com processes your personal information for the following purposes:

  * Sending our newsletter and / or promotional messages
  * To inform you about changes in our services and products

## How long do we keep data?

finalwebsites.com will not keep your personal information for longer than is strictly necessary to achieve the purposes for which your data is collected.

## Share with others

finalwebsites.com only discloses data to third parties when necessary for the implementation of our agreement with you or to fulfill a legal obligation. We share only data with partner where we signed a data processing agreement.

Google Analytics and Clicky are used as our primary web analytics software. Only non identifiable data is sent to Google Analytics and Clicky, including rough geographic locations where available.

All emails, send by our website, are processed by a 3rd party SMTP provider. This provider keeps temporary logs which helps us to detect delivery problems.

In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

## Website visits

finalwebsites.com uses functional, analytic and affiliate cookies. A cookie is a small text file that will be stored in the browser of your computer, tablet or smartphone after the first visit to our website. finalwebsites.com cookies are used with a purely technical functionality. These ensure that the website is working properly, for example, it can remember your preferences and help us to make the website work properly. We can use these cookies and data to optimize our website. We place cookies to track your surfing habits so that we can offer customized content and a better website experience.

### Affiliate cookies

We use on our site different affiliate links. If you follow one of these links, a cookie will be placed while visiting the partner's website. These cookies are used to track a possible commission for sales initiated by our visitors. The cookies value never contains your personal information.

### How to deny cookies

You can opt out of this through your web browser settings and adjust it to no longer store cookies. Alternatively, you can delete information stored previously using these same browser settings.

### Google Analytics web browser opt-out

To provide website visitors more choice on how their data is collected, Google has developed the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. Learn more about the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

## View, edit or delete your data

You have the right to view, correct and delete your personal information. You can send a request for inspection, correction or removal to privacy@finalwebsites.com To ensure that the access request has been made by you, please enclose a copy of your ID to the request. We hereby ask you to blacken your passport and citizen service number in this copy. This is to protect your privacy. finalwebsites.com will respond to your request as soon as possible and guarantee a response within four weeks.

## Security

finalwebsites.com takes the protection of your data seriously and will take appropriate measures to prevent abuse, loss, unauthorized access, unwanted disclosure and unauthorized modification. If you suspect that your data is not properly protected or there is evidence of abuse, please contact privacy@finalwebsites.com

Last changed: July 21, 2018
